RG 183, Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission records
1927-2011, bulk 1953-2011
1953-2011
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission
21.25 cubic feet
The Connecticut River Flood Control Compact was signed into law by President Dwight D. Eisenhower on June 6, 1953. The compact created the Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission for the purpose of promoting inter-state comity between and among the signatory states; assuring adequate storage capacity for impounding waters of the Connecticut River and its tributaries for the protection of life and property from floods; and providing a joint or common agency through which the signatory states, while promoting protecting and preserving to each the local interest and sovereignty of the respective signatory states, may more effectively cooperate in accomplishing the object of flood control and water resources utilization in the basin of the Connecticut River and its tributaries.
RG183
2012-024 (except where noted)
Historical Note
The Connecticut River Flood Control Compact was signed into law by President Dwight D. Eisenhower on June 6, 1953, having been previously authorized by the state legislatures of Connecticut, Massachusetts, New Hampshire and Vermont. The passage of the compact established the Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission. On September 8, 1953, the commissioners signed the compact on behalf of the member states. The Commission consists of twelve members with each member state having three commissioners. By the provisions of the compact the Commission must elect a Chairman, Vice Chairman, Treasurer and Clerk.
The Commission from 1953 to 1982 employed an Executive Director and Secretary. Philip Shutler, Director 1953-1968, was the first director. Shutler, formerly the Vermont Commissioner of Water Resources, remained director until his untimely death in 1968. Shutler was succeeded as director by Nathan Tufts. In 1982, following the resignation of Nathan Tufts, Commissioner 1953-1963, 1966-1968; Director 1968-1982, the positions of director and secretary were consolidated into that of Executive Secretary. Pauline Smiaroski, Secretary 1981-1982 and Executive Secretary 1982-2010, served as the Commission's only employee until her retirement. Beginning in 2010, administrative responsibilities were assumed by the Connecticut River Watershed Council of Greenfield, Massachusetts.
The compact calls for the Commonwealth of Massachusetts to reimburse the State(s) of New Hampshire and Vermont fifty percent of the amount of taxes lost to their political subdivisions for the flood control dams and reservoirs at Surry Mountain, New Hampshire and Union Village, Vermont. The State of Connecticut is to reimburse the Commonwealth of Massachusetts and the State(s) of New Hampshire and Vermont forty percent of the amount of taxes lost to their political subdivisions for flood control dams and reservoirs at Tully, Knightville, and Birch Hill, Massachusetts; at Surry Mountain, New Hampshire; and at Union Village, Vermont. Article V of the Compact stipulates that Massachusetts, New Hampshire and Vermont shall also be reimbursed for any other dam or reservoir constructed by the United States in the Connecticut River Valley. The Commission determines tax losses based on the current tax rate and on the average assessed valuation for a period of five years prior to the acquisition by the Corps of Engineers. The Commission "may" use a general revaluation for the purpose of determining the amount of taxes to be reimbursed. The "may" clause caused significant controversy and the Commission has used multiple formulas to determine the amount of taxes to be reimbursed; most significantly the "Shutler Formula" and the "Curry Formula". Decisions must be ratified by two members from each state. Without unanimity among the signatories decisions are not binding. New Hampshire and Vermont have expressed frustration with the method of determining tax reimbursement but cannot implement changes without agreement from both Connecticut and Massachusetts.
The Commission has maintained multiple offices. The original office occupied from 1953-1979 was in Keene, New Hampshire. In 1979 the Commission moved to Greenfield, Massachusetts. The Commission for reasons of economy moved from Greenfield in 1992, records and office equipment were divided between South Deerfield and the offices of the Massachusetts Department of Environmental Management in Northampton.
Scope and Content
The records are arranged into eleven series which document the organization and activities of the Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission. The series include: Governance, Directors' Files, Executive Secretary Files, Reports and Studies, Subject Files, Press Files, Financial Records, NENYIAC Records, Photographs, Maps and Publications.
Series 1. Governance, 1953-2001, consists primarily of minute books and minutes (loose). The series also contains a copy of the Connecticut River Flood Control Compact and material relating to Commission procedures, e.g. proxy votes.
Series 2. Directors' Files, 1953-1982, contains the files of Philip Shutler (Director, 1953-1968) and Nathan Tufts (Commissioner 1953-1963, 1966-1968; Director 1968-1982). A wide variety of materials that includes personal correspondence as well as official Commission business.
Series 3. Executive Secretary Files, 1982-2003, contains the files of Pauline Smiaroski (Secretary 1981-1982; Executive Secretary 1982-2010). Composed of correspondence; resources for the Commission; updates for commissioners, and stenography notebooks from 1981 to 1985.
Series 4. Reports and Studies, 1954-2010, includes annual reports of the Commission, Connecticut River comprehensive water resources investigations, Executive Secretary reports, land resources studies, and technical data.
Series 5. Subject Files, 1935-2010, includes reports and studies done for/by the Commission, information on dams and reservoirs in the Connecticut River Valley, general correspondence, and miscellaneous documents.
Series 6. Press Files, 1936-1998, contains newspaper clippings relating to the Connecticut River Valley and flood control accumulated by Philip Shutler and Nathan Tufts. The Greenfield Recorder features prominently but articles from Connecticut, New Hampshire, and Vermont newspapers are also featured. Also contains clippings from a clip services utilized by the Commission.
Series 7. Financial Records, 1935-2007, consists of economic losses, tax losses, and repayments; claims and the Commission's financial records. Most documents deal with tax repayments by Connecticut and Massachusetts to New Hampshire and Vermont (including information on tax rates and revaluation). Claims files exist until the early 1970's, when construction of dams ceased.
Series 8. NENYIAC Records, 1952-1956, consists of records relating to the New England-New York Inter-Agency Committee. Documents relate to water supply, water use and water pollution. Also includes correspondence between Philip Shutler and other NENYIAC participants.
Series 9. Photographs, circa 1936-1978, includes photographs of dedication and groundbreaking ceremonies; floods; dams and reservoirs; and miscellaneous unidentified portraits, dams and reservoirs, floods, and publications.
Series 10. Maps, 1942-1966, consist of maps that document real estate around dam and reservoir sites; land acquisition for flood control; potential dam and reservoir sites; relocation of infrastructure for dam and reservoir sites; topographical maps; and watershed maps. The bulk of the maps were prepared by the US Army Corps of Engineers. Map sites include: Ball Mountain, Barre Falls, Birch Hill Reservoir, Conant Brook Dam, Farmington River, Gaysville Dam Reservoir, North Hartland Dam, North Springfield, Otter Brook, Surry Mountain, and Townshend.
Series 11. Publications, 1927-1980, includes dedication programs; pamphlets; newsletter; nine books on floods, flood control and water resources; flood control plans and studies for the Connecticut River; federal hearing transcripts on flood control and Water Resources Planning Act; and related flood control reports and studies from other states. The miscellaneous folder consists of a pamphlet on How to Burn Wood from the Connecticut Forest and Park Association, October, 1939; two pamphlets on the National Rivers and Harbors Congress; a manual on the ABC's of Public Relations; Compendium of Laws on Civil Works, January 2, 1969; Vermont Natural Areas, Report 2, March, 1969; Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin News Letter, May-June, 1970; and the proceedings of the National Rivers and Harbors Congress, Forty-seventh National Convention, Washington, D.C., May 24-27, 1960.
Series 12. Accruals, 1953-2011, consist of newsletters, meeting minutes, financial records, financial reports, timber resources, and tax losses and repayments.
Arrangement
Series 1. Governance, 1953-2001
Series 2. Directors' Files, 1953-1982
Series 3. Executive Secretary Files, 1982-2003
Series 4. Reports and Studies, 1954-2010
Series 5. Subject Files, 1935-2010
Series 6. Press Files, 1936-1998
Series 7. Financial Records, 1935-2007
Series 8. NENYIAC Records, 1952-1956
Series 9. Photographs, circa 1936-1978
Series 10. Maps, 1942-1966
Series 11. Publications, 1927-1980
Series 12. Accruals, 1953-2011
Related Material
website.
Links to the compact, bylaws, recent annual reports and meeting minutes.
Connecticut State Library, Hartford, CT.
Box A-242, CRVFCC, 1957-1969
Box A-426, Thomaston Flood Control Dam Dedication, 1961
Box A-443 (Volume 9) Thomaston Flood Control Dam Dedication Ceremonies, June, 16, 1961
Vermont State Archives, Montpelier, VT.
PRA-00068, Philip Shutler (personal) and Philip Shutler (personal travel), 1936
Vermont State Archives, Montpelier, VT.
Box 38, CRVFCC, 1968/69
Vermont State Archives, Montpelier, VT.
F-05005, CRVFCC, 1969
Vermont State Archives, Montpelier, VT.
National Archives and Records Administration, Waltham MA.
National Archives and Records Administration, Waltham, MA.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission; United States. Army. Corps of Engineers; Connecticut River Watershed Council
Subjects:
Flood control -- Connecticut; Flood control -- Massachusetts; Flood control -- New Hampshire; Flood control -- Vermont; Flood control -- Connecticut River Valley; Dams; Reservoirs; Water conservation; Water resources development -- United States; Connecticut River -- Maps; Floods -- New England
Places:
Connecticut; Massachusetts; New Hampshire; Vermont; Rhode Island; Torrington (Conn.); North Springfield; Farmington (Conn.); Naugatuck (Conn.); New Hartford (Conn.); Norwalk (Conn.); Hartford (Conn.); Putnam (Conn.); Simsbury (Conn.); Waterbury (Conn.); Winsted (Conn.); Unionville (Conn.); Collinsville (Conn.); Southbridge (Mass.); Westfield (Mass.); Worcester (Mass.); Keene (N.H.); Greenfield (Mass.); Woonsocket (R.I.); Manville (R.I.); Townshend (Vt.)
Persons:
Shutler, Philip; Tufts, Nathan; Smiaroski, Pauline; Parker, Alban J.
Document Types:
Agendas; Clippings; Correspondence; Maps; Minutes; Photographs; Pamphlets; Financial records; Notebooks; Publications; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The records in accession 2012-024 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library by the Connecticut River Valley Flood Control Commission on March 9 and 14, 2012. The records in accession 2015-021 were transferred to the State Library by the Department of Energy and Environmental Protection, Inland Water Resources Division on November 25, 2014.
Container List
- Series 1. Governance, 1953-2001
  - Connecticut River Flood Control Compact, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Approval/Disapproval of motions form, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mail vote confirmation - accepted meeting of 12/3/70, subject to ratification, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting logistics, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Proxy explanation, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Resolutions and testimonials, 1958-1980 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Volume 1, 1953 September 8 - 1956 March 27 (Box 1)
  - Volume 2, 1956 June 29 - 1958 September 18 (Box 1)
  - Volume 3, 1958 October 2 - 1960 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Volume 4, 1960 October 13 - 1963 December 20 (Box 1)
  - Volume 5, 1964 June 26 - 1966 June 10 (Box 1)
  - Volume 6, 1966 October 14 - 1969 July 11 (Box 1)
  - Volume 7, 1969 September 26 - 1972 September 26 (Box 1)
  - Volume 8, 1972 December 20 - 1975 March 21 (Box 1)
  - Volume 9, 1975 April 18 - 1977 November 18 (Box 1)
  - Volume 10, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - Minute book Vol. XI, 1979 October 5 - 1982 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minute book Vol. XII, 1982 December 17 - 1988 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minute book Vol. XIII, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minute book, 1995 June 6 - 2001 September 21 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Commission meeting, Hartford, 1955 July 14 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Transcript of tapes made, meeting at Manchester, 1958 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1958 June 26 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1958 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1958 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1958 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1960 October 13 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1960 December 16 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1961 April 7 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1961 June 23 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1961 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1962 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1962 October 31 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1963 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1963 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1963 October 23 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1963 December 20 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1964 April 9 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1964 June 26 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1964 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1965 January 29 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1965 April 9 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1965 June 18 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, 1965 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, 1965 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, 1966 March 18 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1966 June 10 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, 1966 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1966 December 16 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Minutes, 1967 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Minutes, 1967 June 8-9 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, 1967 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Minutes, 1967 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Minutes, 1968 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, 1968 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Minutes, 1968 September 27 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Minutes, summary of, 1968 September - 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Minutes, 1968 October 6 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Minutes, 1969 April 18 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Minutes, 1969 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Minutes, 1969 July 11 - 1970 September 25 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Minutes, 1969 September 26 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Minutes, 1969 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Minutes, 1970 March 20 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Minutes, 1970 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Minutes, 1970 September 25 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Minutes, 1970 December 3 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Minutes, 1971 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Minutes, 1971 June 25 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Minutes, 1971 October 29 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Minutes, 1971 December 3 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Minutes, 1972 March 24 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1972 June 22-23 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1972 September 26-27 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1972 December 20 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1973 April 30 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1973 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1973 September 28 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1974 January 11 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1974 March 22 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1974 June 28 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1974 September 27 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1974 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1975 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1975 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1975 September 26 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1975 December 19 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1976 March 19 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1976 June 25 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1976 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1976 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1977 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1977 June 17 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1977 November 18 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1978 January 13 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1978 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1978 June 23 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1978 September 22 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, 1978 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, 1979 March 30 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, 1979 June 26 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1979 October 5 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, 1979 November 16 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1980 January 18 (Box 3, Folder 33-34)
  - Minutes, 1980 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, 1980 June 6 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Minutes, 1980 July 15 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Minutes, 1980 September 26 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, 1980 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Minutes, 1981 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Minutes, 1981 July 10 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Minutes, 1981 September 25 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Minutes, 1981 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Minutes, special meeting, 1982 January 15 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Minutes, 1982 March 26 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Minutes, 1982 June 18 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Minutes, 1982 September 17 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Minutes, 1982 December 17 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Minutes, 1983 June 17 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Minutes, 1983 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Minutes, 1983 December 9 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Minutes, 1984 June 15 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Minutes, 1984 September 21 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Minutes, 1985 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Minutes, 1985 June 14 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Minutes, 1985 August 13 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Minutes, 1985 September 20 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Minutes, 1985 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Minutes, 1986 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Minutes, 1986 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Minutes, 1986 September 19 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Minutes, 1986 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Minutes, 1987 June 19 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Minutes, 1987 September 18 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Minutes, 1987 December 4 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Minutes, 1988 March (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Minutes, 1988 June 17 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Minutes, 1988 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Minutes, 1988 December 9 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Minutes, 1989 June 16 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Minutes, 1989 September 22 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Minutes, 1989 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Minutes, 1990 June 8 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Minutes, 1990 September 21 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Minutes, 1990 December 7 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Minutes, 1991 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Minutes, 1991 September 20 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Minutes, 1991 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Minutes, 1992 June 19 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Minutes, 1992 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Minutes, 1993 June 18 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Minutes, 1993 September 17 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Minutes, 1993 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Minutes, 1994 June 17 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1994 September 30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1994 December 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1995 June 16 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1995 September 15 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1995 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1996 March 8 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1996 June 21 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1996 September 27 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1996 December 6 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1997 June 13 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1997 September 19 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1997 December 5 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1998 June 12 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1998 September 25 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1998 December 4 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1999 June 4 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1999 September 10 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1999 December 3 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 2000 June 23 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 2000 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 2001 June 15 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 2001 September 21 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 2001 December 7 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Series 2. Directors' Files, 1953-1982
  - Director Philip Shutler Files, 1953-1968
    - Anderson-Nichols and Co., Inc., 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Anderson-Nichols and Co., Inc., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Anderson-Nichols and Co., Inc., 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Boston Soc. Of Civil Engineers, HM Turner/Hurley, 1956-1961 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Connecticut River Flood Control Compact, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Corps of Engineers acquisition reports, 1957-1971 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1954-1959 (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
    - Extra copies for file, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Extra copies - articles etc., 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Flood insurance, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Flood of June 16-18, 1943 upper Connecticut River, 1943-1963 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Flood pictures correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Flood water, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Flood, 1960 clippings and articles, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Goose Bone Prophet, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Hand written notes and miscellaneous correspondence, 1954-1968 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Hell's Canyon, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Hon. F. Ray Keyster Jr., Governor of Vermont, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Hon. Joseph B Johnson, Governor of Vermont, 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Hurricane damage, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - I. S. Menzies, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Jones Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Krisensen and Cummings, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Legislation, 1954-1959 (Box 4, Folder 49-50)
    - Maccafern Gabions of America, Inc., The International, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Massachusetts Committee to Schedule Public Works, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Miscellaneous Shutler correspondence, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 53-54)
    - Natural Rivers and Harbors Congress, Shutler statement, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - National water policy, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Notes on history of Connecticut River Valley, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Photograph listing, Corps of Engineers, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Reclamation Construction Bureau, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Re: Program for Connecticut River flood control dams, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Report - Projects Committee and Resolutions Committee, 42nd Convention of National Rivers and Harbors Congress, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Responses to resolution, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Response to 2nd letter to Gov's, Senators and Representatives of N.E. states, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Review of An Opinion on the Connecticut River Flood Control Compact, 1957-1959 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Vermont Public Service Comm., Charles P. Ross, Chairman, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Schedules of appropriations for further dams, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Schedules of construction, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Senator George D. Aiken (R-VT), 1955-1960 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Senator Ralph E. Flanders (R-VT), 1954-1957 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Shutler correspondence - financial documents, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Shutler testimony, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Shutler testimony - Projects Committee, National Rivers and Harbors Congress, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Soil conservation, 1954-1960 (Box 5, Folder 18)